deardiary.org 2018-08-31

# 

|   | 

DearDiary.Net... has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for our various websites. 

We collect, log and use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is used to gather broad demographic information, to determine very roughly where our visitors come from. 

Our sites use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and settings, and for session management to ensure you can successfully log in to your account. 

Our site's registration form requires users to give us contact information (like name and email address) and demographic information (country, gender etc). We use customer contact information from the registration form to occasionally send the user information about our company. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary. Contact information is used to ensure publishers are accountable for their published works and indeed credited for their works should a third party (including DearDiary.Net) wish to use such works. The gathered information is never disseminated outside of the company except where required for legal purposes. 

**NOTICE TO PARENTS:** To comply with the United States Law for the protection of your childs privacy (Children Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not ask for the age of any child. However, if you believe your child has an account with us, and you wish to request that the details are removed from our database, please mail [support@deardiary.net](mailto:support@deardiary.net) to request this. You will need to be prepared to prove you are the childs parent or guardian, and please note that we cannot (and aren't obliged by COPPA) to bar your child from using our service, however we will (as parents ourselves) treat each case on an individual basis and do our best to help. This may simply mean the removal of the childs email address from our system and therefore restricting access to areas of the service that absolutely require that information. 

**NOTICE TO UNDER 13's:** If you reside in the United States of America, this applies to you. The law of your country states that if we are aware that you are under 13, we must get your parents consent to hold data that can identify you. This means, that we must remove your email address and any other personal information about your account, if we discover or are made aware that you are under 13. Unlike other diary sites we do not believe in banning any segment of the population, however, there are certain features of the site that absolutely require your email address. So, if we become aware that you are under 13, some features of the site will be disabled until we can gain your parents/guardians consent to hold your email address. **Please do NOT give information that may enable someone to know who you are! The internet, just like a crowded park or shopping mall can be a dangerous place. Do not give information to anyone about who you are.**

Demographic information (country, etc) can sometimes be used for statistical analysis, but in such cases the analysis will be of a broad nature and will not be related or relateable to any individual user(s) of the site. 

Our sites contains links to other sites. **DearDiary.Net** are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

## Public Forums

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. If we are made aware that you are under 13 years of age and reside in the USA, we may have to restrict your access to ensure that we comply with your laws. You will still be able to access most of the sites, though you will have to send any posts to our support address so that we can ensure there is no personally identifying information included in them. 

## Security

This site has various security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 

These measures include, but are not necessarily limited to; 

  * Regular (nightly) offsite backups 
  * Access to the core server is only allowed using SSH2 technologies 
  * Access to SSH2 is only granted to users with previously uploaded public certificates. Password access to the server is forbidden 
  * Limited access, even via SSH2, only to people known personally by DearDiary.Net staff. 
  * Regular monitoring of server logs for suspicious activity 
  * Individual SysAdmins are radio paged if anything looks wrong on the system. 
  * A plethora of other security measures that we would not wish to divulge! 

## Choice/Opt-Out

Our site does not provide your information to other companies (unless ordered by a court of law). It is possible, to opt out of receiving e-mails of an administrative nature, or promotional nature by de-selecting (unticking) the appropriate tick box in the account details screens. The appropriate screen can be found at <http://www.deardiary.net/common/updateuser.php>, you will be required to enter your user name and password. 

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications and to no longer receive our service. 

  1. You can send email to [support@deardiary.net](mailto:support@deardiary.net)

## Correct/Update

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided. 

  1. Login to your account and click the 'Personal' link in your members button bar. Or click [here](http://www.deardiary.net/common/updateuser.php)
  2. email [support@deardiary.net](mailto:support@deardiary.net)

## Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact us on our correspondance address; Email: [support@deardiary.net](http://www.deardiary.net/support) |   |
